<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Home</title>
    <link>https://kossi-akplaka.github.io/Portfolio/post/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language><atom:link href="https://kossi-akplaka.github.io/Portfolio/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Project:  Product Demand Forecasting</title>
      <link>https://kossi-akplaka.github.io/Portfolio/post/project1/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kossi-akplaka.github.io/Portfolio/post/project1/</guid>
      <description>Product demand forecasting helps businesses make informed decisions about inventory management, production planning, and pricing strategies based on predicted demand which lead to improved profitability, reduced waste, and increased customer satisfaction. Collected the relevant data from Kaggle for the time series, preprocessed the data by removing missing values, outliers, and irrelevant variables and performed feature engineering. Decomposed the time series into its components, including trend, seasonality, and noise and made the time series stationary, meaning its statistical properties remain constant over time.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Mortgage Loan Approval Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://kossi-akplaka.github.io/Portfolio/post/project3/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kossi-akplaka.github.io/Portfolio/post/project3/</guid>
      <description>Created a dashboard that can track and display key metrics related to mortgage loan approval rates, such as approval rates by demographics or loan types. This can help lenders monitor loan approval rates in real-time and identify areas for improvement. Created custom data visualizations in Power BI to help users quickly identify trends and patterns in the loan approval data and implemented data cleansing and data transformation techniques in Power Query to prepare data for analysis For more, please check out my github page at https://github.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Project: Rental Property Price Prediction/ Dashboard</title>
      <link>https://kossi-akplaka.github.io/Portfolio/post/project2/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://kossi-akplaka.github.io/Portfolio/post/project2/</guid>
      <description>Predicting rental property prices can help businesses, such as real estate agencies and property management companies, make data-driven decisions about property investments, pricing strategies, and marketing campaigns. Collected the relevant data from Kaggle for the time series, preprocessed the data by removing missing values, outliers, and irrelevant variables and performed feature engineering. Created a dashboard to display insights on rental property prices, such as trends and patterns in pricing data, in a visually appealing and easy-to-understand format.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
